<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CPO (CYBERTEC-PG-Operator) on CYBERTEC-PG-Operator</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/CYBERTEC-pg-operator/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CPO (CYBERTEC-PG-Operator) on CYBERTEC-PG-Operator</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 14:26:51 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/CYBERTEC-pg-operator/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>via Blockstorage (pvc)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/CYBERTEC-pg-operator/backup/pvc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 14:26:51 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/CYBERTEC-pg-operator/backup/pvc/</guid>
      <description>Backups are essential for databases. From broken storage to deployments gone wrong, backups often save the day. Starting with pg_dump, which was released in the late 1990s, to the archiving of WAL files (PostgreSQL 8.0 / 2005) and pg_basebackup (PostgreSQL 9.0 / 2010), PostgreSQL already offers built-in options for backups and restores based on logical and physical backups.&#xA;Backups with pgBackRest CPO relies on pgBackRest as its backup solution, a tried-and-tested tool with extensive backup and restore options.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>via S3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/CYBERTEC-pg-operator/backup/aws/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 14:26:51 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/CYBERTEC-pg-operator/backup/aws/</guid>
      <description>Backups are essential for databases. From broken storage to deployments gone wrong, backups often save the day. Starting with pg_dump, which was released in the late 1990s, to the archiving of WAL files (PostgreSQL 8.0 / 2005) and pg_basebackup (PostgreSQL 9.0 / 2010), PostgreSQL already offers built-in options for backups and restores based on logical and physical backups.&#xA;Backups with pgBackRest CPO relies on pgBackRest as its backup solution, a tried-and-tested tool with extensive backup and restore options.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>via GCS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/CYBERTEC-pg-operator/backup/gcs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 14:26:51 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/CYBERTEC-pg-operator/backup/gcs/</guid>
      <description>This chapter describes the use of pgBackRest in combination with Google Cloud Storage (gcs). It is not absolutely necessary to operate a Kubernetes on the Google Cloud Platform. However, as with any cloud storage, the efficiency and therefore the duration of a backup depends on the connection.&#xA;Precondition: a gcs-bucket and a priviledged role is needed for this chapter. Create a gcs-bucket on the google cloud console Create a priviledged service-role Modifying the Cluster Backups on PVC (PersistentVolumeClaim) When using block storage, the operator creates an additional pod that acts as a repo host.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>via Azure-Blob</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/CYBERTEC-pg-operator/backup/azure_blob/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 14:26:51 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/CYBERTEC-pg-operator/backup/azure_blob/</guid>
      <description>Backups are essential for databases. From broken storage to deployments gone wrong, backups often save the day. Starting with pg_dump, which was released in the late 1990s, to the archiving of WAL files (PostgreSQL 8.0 / 2005) and pg_basebackup (PostgreSQL 9.0 / 2010), PostgreSQL already offers built-in options for backups and restores based on logical and physical backups.&#xA;Backups with pgBackRest CPO relies on pgBackRest as its backup solution, a tried-and-tested tool with extensive backup and restore options.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Project</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/CYBERTEC-pg-operator/project/project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 14:26:51 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/CYBERTEC-pg-operator/project/project/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Container Images</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/CYBERTEC-pg-operator/project/project-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 14:26:51 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/CYBERTEC-pg-operator/project/project-copy/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Architecture</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/CYBERTEC-pg-operator/architecture/architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 14:26:51 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/CYBERTEC-pg-operator/architecture/architecture/</guid>
      <description>This chapter covers all important aspects relating to the architecture of CPO and the associated components. In addition to the underlying Kubertnetes, the various components and their interaction for the operation of a PostgreSQL cluster are analysed.&#xA;Brief overview of the components Network-Traffic PG-Cluster-intern Traffic With internal PG cluster-internal traffic, we are talking about all traffic that is necessary for the operation of the cluster itself. This includes&#xA;Communication for the sync of the replicas: pg_basebackup &amp;amp; streaming replication Communication with pgBackRest (if configured) Backups WAL archiving replica-create for new replicas The figure below shows the internal traffic flows with pgBackRest based on block storage (left) or cloud storage (right)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PostgreSQL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/CYBERTEC-pg-operator/crd/crd-postgresql/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 14:26:51 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/CYBERTEC-pg-operator/crd/crd-postgresql/</guid>
      <description>postgresql Name Type required Description apiVersion string true acid.zalando.do/v1 kind string true metadata object true spec object true status object false spec Name Type required Description backup object false Enables the definition of a customised backup solution for the cluster teamId string true name of the team the cluster belongs to numberOfInstances Int true Number of nodes of the cluster dockerImages string false Define a custom image to override the default schedulerName string false Define a custom Name to override the default spiloRunAsUser string false Define an User id which should be used for the pods spiloRunAsGroup string false Define an Group id which should be used for the pods spiloFSGroup string false Persistent Volumes for the pods in the StatefulSet will be owned and writable by the group ID specified.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operator-Configuration</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/CYBERTEC-pg-operator/crd/crd-operator-configurator/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 14:26:51 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/CYBERTEC-pg-operator/crd/crd-operator-configurator/</guid>
      <description>Name Type default Description enable_crd_registration boolean true crd_categories string all enable_lazy_spilo_upgrade boolean false enable_pgversion_env_var boolean true enable_spilo_wal_path_combat boolean false etcd_host string kubernetes_use_configmaps boolean false docker_image string sidecars list enable_shm_volume boolean true workers int 8 max_instances int -1 min_instances int -1 resync_period string 30m repair_period string 5m set_memory_request_to_limit boolean false debug_logging boolean true enable_db_access boolean true spilo_privileged boolean false spilo_allow_privilege_escalation boolean true watched_namespace string * major-upgrade-specific Name Type default Description major_version_upgrade_mode string off major_version_upgrade_team_allow_list string minimal_major_version string 9.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quickstart</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/CYBERTEC-pg-operator/quickstart/quickstart/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 14:26:51 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/CYBERTEC-pg-operator/quickstart/quickstart/</guid>
      <description>We can tell and document so much about our project but it seems you just want to get started. Let us show you the fastest way to use CPO.&#xA;Preconditions git helm (optional) kubectl or oc Let&amp;rsquo;s start Step 1 - Preparations To get started, you can fork our tutorial repository on Github and then download it. CYBERTEC-operator-tutorials&#xA;GITHUB_USER=&amp;#39;[YOUR_USERNAME]&amp;#39; git clone https://github.com/$GITHUB_USER/CYBERTEC-operator-tutorials.git cd CYBERTEC-operator-tutorials Step 2 - Install the Operator Two options are available for the installation:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Setup local Kubernetes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/CYBERTEC-pg-operator/installation/playground.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 14:26:51 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/CYBERTEC-pg-operator/installation/playground.md/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Install CPO</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/CYBERTEC-pg-operator/installation/installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 14:26:51 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/CYBERTEC-pg-operator/installation/installation/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites For the installation you either need our CPO tutorial repository or you install CPO directly from our registry. Exception: Installation via Operatorhub (Openshift only)&#xA;CPO-Tutorial-Repository To get started, you can fork our tutorial repository on Github and then download it. CYBERTEC-operator-tutorials&#xA;GITHUB_USER=&amp;#39;[YOUR_USERNAME]&amp;#39; git clone https://github.com/$GITHUB_USER/CYBERTEC-operator-tutorials.git cd CYBERTEC-operator-tutorials CPO-Registry Create Namespace # kubectl kubectl create namespace cpo # oc oc create namespace cpo Install CPO There are several ways to install CPO:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operator-Configuration</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/CYBERTEC-pg-operator/installation/configuration_operator/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 14:26:51 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/CYBERTEC-pg-operator/installation/configuration_operator/</guid>
      <description>Users who are already used to working with PostgreSQL from Baremetal or VMs are already familiar with the need for various files to configure PostgreSQL. These include&#xA;postgresql.conf pg_hba.conf &amp;hellip; Although these files are available in the container, direct modification is not planned. As part of the declarative mode of operation of the operator, these files are defined via the operator. The modifying intervention within the container also represents a contradiction to the immutability of the container.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PostgreSQL 16</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/CYBERTEC-pg-operator/extensions/pg16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 14:26:51 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/CYBERTEC-pg-operator/extensions/pg16/</guid>
      <description>The extensions listed are included in the standard images. This list refers to PostgreSQL 16. Name Default Version Comment adminpack 2.1 Administrative functions for PostgreSQL amcheck 1.3 Functions for verifying relation integrity autoinc 1.0 Functions for autoincrementing fields bloom 1.0 Bloom access method - signature file based index btree_gin 1.3 Support for indexing common datatypes in GIN btree_gist 1.7 Support for indexing common datatypes in GiST citext 1.6 Data type for case-insensitive character strings credcheck 2.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Release Notes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/CYBERTEC-pg-operator/release_notes/release_notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 14:26:51 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/CYBERTEC-pg-operator/release_notes/release_notes/</guid>
      <description>0.7.0 Features Monitoring-Sidecar integrated via CRD Start with Monitoring Password-Hash per default set to scram-sha-256 pgBackRest with blockstorage using RepoHost Internal Certification-Management for RepoHost-Certificates Compatible with PG17Beta2 Changes API Change acid.zalan.do is replaced by cpo.opensource.cybertec.at - If you&amp;rsquo;re updating your Operator from previous Versions, please check this HowTo Migrate to new API Patroni-Compatibility has increased to Version 3.3.2 pgBackRest-Compatbility has increased to Version 2.52.1 Revision of the restore process Revision of the backup jobs Operator now using Rocky9 as Baseimage Updates Go-Package to 1.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
